Bryce Dawson, Computer Science Graduate

07955642782, bryce_dawson@outlook.com

LINKS

Coursework Website, Honours project Website, LinkedIn Profile

PROFILE

Soon to be a Computer Science graduate from Robert Gordon's University. Seeking employment in any area of computer science to which I feel I could bring many useful and necessary skills. I am hard-working and enjoy working both as a team and individually to ensure that tasks get completed to the highest standard.

I attended Meldrum Academy from 2013-2018 where I completed my National 5's and Highers. During my time at the academy, I was appointed as head boy. This role gave me a large boost in my confidence in being able to speak to groups of people from small meetings to the entire school.

I get along very well with people, and I feel that I am an easy person to speak to, I enjoy interacting with customers and do my utmost to make their experience enjoyable so that they want to return. I am very determined and when I'm set a task I will always complete it to the highest standard that I can as I set very high goals for myself.

My biggest passion is football and has been since I was young, I am currently signed to Inverurie Locos Works and loaned out to Hall Russell Juniors. Playing football has helped me develop my team-building skills and helped me take responsibility when needed, for example, I captained the school football team for 3 years and captained the under 17's Inverurie Locos development football team and under 19's juvenile team. This has helped me to gain vital leadership skills but has also taught me how to get along easily with many different people. This allows me to have a balance between getting on with other people and being able to take control and make decisions when needed.

I also own a full clean UK driver's license.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dec 2021 — Present

Customer Team Leader, Eros Retail

At present, I am a Customer Team Leader at Eros Retail, Inverurie where I have been in the position since December 2021. I thoroughly enjoy my job and feel like it has given me more confidence in being able to deal with problems and issues by myself without needing to look for guidance. It has also taught me a great deal about customer relations and how to deal with all types of customers who come into the store. I really enjoy speaking to customers and getting to know them as I feel can create good relations with them. My main responsibility is very similar to my previous role at Co-op as a Team leader but with additional tasks such as cashing up tills at the end of the night/recounting tills from the night before.

Feb 2021 — Dec 2021

Customer Team Leader, Co-op

As a Customer Team Leader, my responsibilities increased from previously being a Team Member. I was now responsible for training new staff which we had started within the store to ensure that they got the best start to their work at the Co-op, and they had the right tools to get their work done effectively. I needed to complete

reductions and waste for any products in the shop. This was important as it required me to be very vigilant with what products needed to come off of the shop floor to ensure customers did not purchase any out of date items. I was also given the responsibility to lock the shop up at the end of the night when on shift. This required me to complete all the closing procedures ensuring the shop was secure for the following day.

Mar 2019 — Feb 2021

Customer Team Member, Co-op

As a Customer Team Member, I was required to mainly serve customers who came into the shop to process their purchases. I felt this job further increased my communication skills as I learned how to deal with different types of customers to ensure that all customers were satisfied with their shopping experience.

Mar 2018 — Mar 2019

Park Operative, Skyline Trampoline Park

My job at Skyline was working around the trampoline areas to ensure all customers were kept safe and ensuring no accidents occurred. This job really kick-started my interest in being in a customer-related job as I always needed to make sure that the customers were firstly being able to enjoy their selves at the park but also that they were acting safely and responsibly.

May 2016 — Aug 2016

Banquet Waiter, Hudsons Catering

My first job was as a waiter catering at weddings for a local hotel, I feel that this high-pressure environment & the element of team working allows me to strive & work to the best of my abilities. It gives me very good time management skills as I needed to make sure I was in on time to work but also that I was working towards a deadline that needed to be met as certain things need to be done by certain times during my shift.

EDUCATION

Sep 2018 — May 2022

BSc HONS Computer Science, The Robert Gordon University

Graduating with a First Degree BSC HONS in Computer Science after receiving the following grades in my final year of studies.

Enterprise Web Systems - A, Honours Project Semester 1 - A, Honours Project Semester 2 - A, Computer Vision - A, Data Visualisation - B, Languages and Compilers - B, Advanced Artificial Intelligence - B, Human-Computer Interaction - C.

For my Honours project, I created a Smart Cities Visualisation which allows users to access a website I have created to view and compare the traffic volume, air quality, bus stops and recycling points in Aberdeen during the first COVID-19 lockdown to after lockdown had ended. I then presented this at the University and got very good feedback on my work. You can find and explore the website here - Aberdeen Traffic Viewer

Aug 2012 - May 2018

Meldrum Academy

Highers:

English - B, Biology - B, P.E. - B, Maths - D, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, Computing Science - B, Administration and IT - B, Geography - B, Computing Science - B, C

National 5's:

English - A, Maths - A, Physics - A, Biology - A, P.E. - A, Computing Science - A, RMPS - C

SKILLS

Java Programming

Ability to Work in a Team

Python

Agile Software Development

Effective Team Leader

AWARDS

Aug 2016 - May 2018

Career Ready

During my time at academy, I completed the Career Ready program which gives students access to real-world applications to get them ready for life after school which only allows a small number of students from each school to take part in. The course has scheduled workshops which I attended, these covered areas such as networking, career pathways, career skills e.g. The whole experience gave me vital workplace skills which I have felt have helped me greatly in all aspects of life. The course also gave me a mentor which has helped me apply for previous jobs, written references and helped me with my application to University. The main part of the Career Ready program was the summer internship which I completed in the summer of 2017 at CNRL.

INTERNSHIPS

Jul 2017 — Aug 2017

Career Ready, Computer Programmer, CNRL

Aberdeen

During my internship, I got a chance to work in multiple different areas of CNRL to gain an understanding of each department and its roles. I mainly worked as part of the Maximo Application Project Team to help reduce downtime for their oil rigs and how to best optimise performance within areas of the company. I also worked in the Information management team to help with updating archives by using Documentation Worktop,

I got the chance to use different programming languages that I was unfamiliar with at the beginning of my internship but some of the skills I had gained I could apply here which then helped me quickly get to grips with the new software & allowed me to start to use it successfully. I also learned some very valuable team skills as I had to work with people who I did not know & had to cooperate with them well so that we could get the tasks completed which also boosted my overall confidence in myself. At the end of the Internship, I gave a presentation to the staff I had worked with about what I felt I had learned & what I got out of it.

REFERENCES

John Isaacs from Robert Gordon University

j.p.isaacs@rgu.ac.uk

Lee Black from Eros Retail

+44 7860 261602

LANGUAGES English Native speaker